{
  "reference_number": "2546",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "Climate is too serious an issue to delay action on. We need to take far reaching and rapid action now to address this."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "We need to take rapid and drastic action to address climate change. This means moving our electricity generation to 100%\n\n carboNZero electricity. Switching our transport fleet to electric vehicles and low carbon forms of transport. We need to incorporate\n agriculture and massively reduce our dairy herd. Dairy is particularly bad in that as well as CH4 emissions, Dairy negatively effects the\n\n water quality of our rivers and recent information has demonstrated that Fontera are sourcing Palm Kernel from the destruction of\n rainforest in Indonesia."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "It makes sense that the reforestation occurs in New Zealand. In this way we will see the benefits from our actions to reduce our\n emissions. We should aim for 100% of our electricity to be produced from carboNZero generation. We need to adopt all the available\n\n technology to address this problem. We need to be able to respond rapidly with the best technology available. For example, the\n electrification of our transport and the reduction of intensive farming practices. All sectors of the economy have opportunities to\n reduce their carbon emissions and these need to be incentivised."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It should only be allowed to be revised to enforce a stricter target. With feedback mechanisms in place with the permafrost melting in\n the Arctic we are rapidly running out of time to be able to slow down or reverse the impacts of climate change."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Only if they a strict enough to result in positive change."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "The budget should be able to be moved but only in a positive direction. We cannot afford to delay addressing this climate change."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The budget should be able to be moved but only in a positive direction. We cannot afford to delay addressing this climate change."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We need to incorporate Dairy into the equation. We need to immediately stop the expansion of dairy due to its negative impact on the\n\nlocal and global climate. This will be difficult as there will be considerable pressure to keep business as usual even though it is\ndestructive to the environment."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We need to monitor our progress and put in place legislation which holds the government accountable to its progress towards\n\nmeeting these goals."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": "The NZ ETS has not worked and the only way for it to work is to give it teeth. The ETS should purchase all its credits from NZ certified\n\nprogrammes."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "This is inevitable. It will be helpful to cost in the effect of climate change events on the economy. It will add emphasis to addressing\nthe problem."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "I agree with the proposed functions"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I am concerned that the Zero Carbon Act will not be resilient against powerful lobby groups. The existing oil and gas sector, the dairy\nindustry, farming in general, the automotive industry and the big players in the electricity sector will all try to water down and slow\n\ndown the necessary action that we need to take. I am also concerned that international trade agreements may also slow down\nprogress. It is important that the positive opportunities that arise from addressing climate change and the moral obligation to do so\n\nare highlighted. If we delay action it will be far more expensive and we will be less likely to succeed. I believe that all effort needs to be\ndone to get agreement across all sectors of business and the community if this is going to work.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
